Doctor Who (1963) 04x09  The Evil of the Daleks (Episode 6)
《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集 《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第六部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
Sincro: wyxchari
DOCTOR: It's a game, Jamie! They're playing a game!
这是个游戏, Jamie, 他们在跟我玩游戏！
DOCTOR: A rather amusing little game, don't you think so Jamie.
一个很有意思的小游戏，你不觉得吗 Jamie？
DOCTOR: We've done it! Maxtible, they've got the "Human Factor". We've done it!
我们搞定了, Maxtible, 他们得到了“人类特质”, 我们搞定了！
DOCTOR: What are they doing now? Look, they're all joining in. They're playing train!
他们在干什么？看, 他们都连起来了, 他们在玩火车！
DALEK: Train, train, train, train.
火车, 火车, 火车, 火车
DOCTOR: Oh... oh, now what is it? Oh, we're on the roundabout. They're playing roundabout.
噢。。噢, 现在玩什么？哦, 我们被包围了, 他们在玩转圈圈
DOCTOR: Oh, I'm getting dizzy. Oh dear. Oh, oh, ho, ho, oh. I'm dizzy! Oh, ho, ho. I'm dizzy.
噢, 我要晕了。哦, 天啦, 哦, 哦, 哦, 我晕了！哦, 我晕了
DALEK: Diz-yy, diz-yy, dizzy Doctor.
晕-了, 晕-了, 晕-了-博士
DOCTOR: Maxtible, do you hear that? They've got a sense of humour!
Maxtible, 你听到了吗？他们有了幽默感！
MAXTIBLE: I'm glad you are so easily amused.
我很高兴你是如此容易被逗乐
MAXTIBLE: Well, I congratulate you, Doctor. They are almost human.
很好, 恭喜你, 博士。他们很人类
DOCTOR: They are!
的确是！
MAXTIBLE: And I will now leave you to your little game.
我就不耽误你玩你的小游戏了
DOCTOR: Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢你
JAMIE: Well, how old are they now, Doctor - mentally?
那, 他们有多大年龄, 博士 —— 从思维上说？
DOCTOR: Oh, they're just young children, but they'll grow up very fast - within a matter of hours.
噢, 他们还只是小孩子, 不过他们会长得很快 —— 只要几个小时
DOCTOR: Now, uh... come here all of you. Come along, gather round.
Come here. Now then, come along, come along.
现在, 你们都过来, 到这里来, 靠拢, 到这里来。来吧, 过来
DALEK: Who is this?
这是谁？
DOCTOR: Oh, this is Jamie. He's a friend.
哦, 这是 Jamie, 他是个朋友
DALEK: Friend. Hello, friend.
朋友。你好, 朋友
DOCTOR: Well, say hello Jamie.
很好, 说你好, Jamie
JAMIE: Hello.
你好
DOCTOR: You know what a friend is, don't you? It's somebody who
...who likes you - who wants to help you and share with you.
你知道什么是朋友, 对不？就是喜欢你的人 - 愿意帮助你, 跟你一起分享的人
DOCTOR: There we are.
好啦, 都到了
DALEK: What have you done?
你做了什么?
DOCTOR: I have given you all names. Alpha, Beta and Omega.
我给你们都取了名字：阿尔法、贝塔、欧米伽
DALEK: Alpha, Beta, Omega. Alpha, Beta, Omega. Alpha, Beta, Omega.
阿尔法、贝塔、欧米伽, 阿尔法、贝塔、欧米伽, 阿尔法、贝塔、欧米伽
DOCTOR: Yes, yes, yes. now... now, this is Jamie and I am Doctor. We are friends.
是的, 是的, 是的。现在。。现在, 这位是 Jamie, 我是博士, 我们是朋友
DALEK: Friends, friends, Jamie, Doctor, friends, friends.
朋友, 朋友, Jamie, 博士, 朋友, 朋友。
DALEK: We must go now. We are called.
我们得走了, 被召唤了
DOCTOR: Go? Go where? What do you mean, "go"?
走？去哪儿？你们什么意思, “走”？
DALEK: All Daleks are ordered to return to Skaro.
所有 Daleks 都被命令返回 Skaro
DOCTOR: Return to Skaro? But, that's the Dalek planet.
返回 Skaro? 但是, 那是 Dalek 的星球
DALEK: Friend.
朋友
JAMIE: But if the Daleks are returning to Skaro, where's Victoria?
如果 Daleks 全都要返回 Skaro, 那 Victoria 呢？
DOCTOR: Victoria! We left her in the secret passage. Come on - follow me!
Victoria! 我们把她忘在秘密通道了, 快, 跟我来！
MAXTIBLE: I assure you, my dear Waterfield, Victoria is perfectly safe.
我向你保证, 我亲爱的 Waterfield, Victoria 现在非常的安全
WATERFIELD: But where is she?
但她在哪儿？
MAXTIBLE: The Daleks have released her.
Dalek 已经放了她
WATERFIELD: Released?
放了？
MAXTIBLE: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
是的, 是的, 是的
WATERFIELD: Well, then, where is she?
那, 她在哪儿？
MAXTIBLE: She's probably lying down. Ruth will be taking care of her. You may be sure of that.
她很可能已经睡觉了, Ruth 在照顾她, 你可以放心
WATERFIELD: Not Ruth, no. I saw her and Mollie helping
Arthur Terrall into a dog-cart not half an hour since.
不会是 Ruth, 不。我看见她和 Mollie 扶着 Arthur Terrall 进了一辆马车, 不到半个小时前
MAXTIBLE: Ruth and Terrall?
Ruth 和 Terrall?
WATERFIELD: Yes. Surely you knew they were leaving?
是, 当然你知道他们离开吧？
MAXTIBLE: Oh, yes, yes, indeed, yes. It, it slipped my memory.
噢, 是的, 是的, 的确是。我都忘了。
MAXTIBLE: Umm... As you see, I'm going for a little trip myself.
I... No doubt, I shall join them.
如你所见, 我也要有一段小旅程了。无疑地, 我会跟他们会合
MAXTIBLE: Well, possibly she's, ah... taking a stroll in the garden.
Go along and see. Go along and see.
。那。。她可能正在花园散步呢。去看看吧, 去看看
WATERFIELD: Yes
好吧
MAXTIBLE: Well, go along man! Go along and see. Find your Victoria.
嗯, 去吧, 去看看, 找到你的 Victoria
(Maxtible gets his traveling bag from a cupboard.)
（Maxtible 从橱柜中拿出了他的旅行包）
MAXTIBLE: Stupid, stupid girl.
蠢人, 愚蠢的女孩儿
(Then he moves to a grey box on the floor and starts to examine it.)
（然后他走近地板上的一个灰色盒子, 开始研究）
DALEK: What are you doing?
你在干什么？
MAXTIBLE: Merely, ah... looking.
只不过是。。。看看
DALEK: Do not touch the instrument.
不要碰这些仪器
MAXTIBLE: What is that box for?
这个盒子是做什么的
DALEK: Do not question. You have your orders.
不要提问, 你要遵循你的命令
MAXTIBLE: Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes. To... To bring the Doctor
and his companion to you here for our little trip.
噢, 是, 是, 是, 是。要把博士和他的同伴给你们带来, 一起进行我们的小旅程
DALEK: Yes
是的
MAXTIBLE: And then... The secret - you will give it to me?
然后。。那个秘密 - 你们会给我的吧？
DALEK: Yes.
是的
MAXTIBLE: The formula - the transmutation formula.
秘方 - 转换秘方
DALEK: Yes. Obey your order. Do not delay.
是的。服从你的命令, 不要延误
(The Dalek returns to the cabinet.)
（Dalek 返回到柜子里去了）
(Maxtible continues examing the machine.)
（Maxtible 继续研究那个机器）
MAXTIBLE: Doctor, Doctor! Doctor!
博士, 博士, 博士！
MAXTIBLE: Oh, Waterfield, how I'm delighted you've come back.
噢, Waterfield, 我很高兴你回来了
MAXTIBLE: Now will you please go and find the Doctor and his companion
Jamie and bring them here to me? It is a matter of some urgency.
你能不能去找到博士和他的同伴 Jamie, 把他们带来见我？这里有点急事
WATERFIELD: Maxtible?
MAXTIBLE: Oh, what is it?
哦, 什么事？
WATERFIELD: What have you "arranged" with the Daleks?
你跟 Daleks 在策划什么事情？
MAXTIBLE: The Daleks; nothing.
Daleks？ 没有啊
WATERFIELD: What formula did they promise you?
他们承诺给你什么秘方？
MAXTIBLE: No formula whatever.
没什么秘方
WATERFIELD: What are you doing? You've sold yourself to them, haven't you?
你做些什么？你把自己卖给了他们, 是不是？
MAXTIBLE: You fool!
傻人
WATERFIELD: Yes, I'm a fool - a fool not to have realised before
that it was you who brought this misery down on us.
是的, 我很傻, 傻到一直都没有意识到, 带给我们这些悲剧的, 正是你
MAXTIBLE: You, you never did understand anything, did you?
Well, metal into gold. That's what the Daleks are going to give me.
你, 你从来就什么都不明白, 是吧。好吧, 金属变成金子, 那就是 Dalek 要给我的秘方
MAXTIBLE: Now do you begin to understand? The secret of the transmutation of metal into gold.
现在你明白了吗？将金属变成金子的秘密
WATERFIELD: Do you imagine I care about that?! Where is Victoria?
你以为我在乎那个吗？ Victoria 在哪儿！
MAXTIBLE: I've not the remotest idea.
我完全不知道
WATERFIELD: Yes, you have, and you're going to tell me!
你知道, 而且你会告诉我！
MAXTIBLE: Get your hands off my throat. Let go of me! Murder!
Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Murder! Oh.
别用手掐我的喉咙, 放开我！谋杀啊, 谋杀, 谋杀。。。。。噢
MAXTIBLE: Oh, what are you doing?
噢, 你在干什么？
DALEK: Where is the Doctor?
博士在哪儿？
MAXTIBLE: Well, I had no time to bring him.
呃——我还没时间把他带来
DALEK: Hurry. That is an order.
快去, 这是命令
MAXTIBLE: What is that box for? Will you tell me?
这个箱子是做什么的, 你能告诉我妈
DALEK: We are destroying this area.
我们要摧毁这片区域
MAXTIBLE: But you can't do that. Turn it off! You cannot destroy my house!
你不能这么做, 关掉它！你不能摧毁我的房子！
DALEK: Bring the Doctor. Obey! Immediately!
把博士带来, 服从！马上！
MAXTIBLE: But, uh... the secret. If you destroy my laboratory,
the secret is useless! You promised me.
但是。。秘密呢？如果你毁了我的实验室, 秘密就没有用了！你许诺过我的
MAXTIBLE: They must be out of their minds! Destroy my laboratory?
The very idea... Well, well.
他们一定是疯了！要毁了我的实验室？这个想法。。。好吧, 好吧
MAXTIBLE: But, oh, goodness gracious me, only two minutes. Doctor, Doctor, Doctor...
只是, 噢, 乖乖, 只有两分钟了。博士, 博士, 博士。。。
(Maxtible enters the Dalek cabinet.)
（Maxtible 也进了 Dalek 那个柜子）
DALEK: All Daleks return to Skaro.
所有 Daleks 返回 Skaro
(The Daleks begin to move into the cabinet.)
（所有 Dalek 陆续进入柜子）
DALEK: All Daleks return to Skaro.
所有 Daleks 返回 Skaro
DALEK: And the prisoners?
囚犯怎么安排？
DALEK: They are already in transit.
他们已经在路上了
WATERFIELD: Doc... Dalek... Doctor.
博。。Dalek。。博士。。
DOCTOR: Waterfield, what's happened to you?
Waterfield, 你怎么了？
WATERFIELD: Doc... Doctor, Daleks are going to destroy... house. Can't turn it off.
博。。博士, Daleks 要毁灭。。房子, 我关不掉
DOCTOR: But, this is a time switch.
是, 这是个计时器
JAMIE: Well, if you can't turn it off, surely...
不过, 如果你不能关掉他, 还是可以。。。
DOCTOR: No, wait a minute. Eighty-nine, eighty-eight, eighty-seven.
Just about a minute, that's all we've got.
不, 等等, 89, 88, 87.。。只有一分多钟了, 我们只有这么多
JAMIE: Well, toss it out the window then.
那, 把它扔到窗户外面去啊
DOCTOR: This isn't a firework. We'd have to toss this half a mile.
We'll have to follow the Daleks to Skaro.
这可不是烟花, 我们得把它扔到半英里以外才行。我们只能跟着 Daleks 到 Skaro 去了
DOCTOR: Jamie, open the doors. Come along.
Jamie, 把门打开, 快来
JAMIE: Doctor, they're locked. They won't budge!
博士, 门被锁住了, 推不动
MAXTIBLE: Cupboard in the alcove. The time machine.
壁橱里面的柜子, 那个时间机器
DOCTOR: Time machine! Jamie, give me a hand. Come on.
Quickly. Quickly. Here, now... Here, take this.
时间机器！Jamie, 给我搭把手, 来, 快, 快点, 现在。。。这里, 抓住这个
(The Doctor and Jamie drag the Dalek's time machine from the alcove.)
（博士和 Jamie 竭力把 Dalek 的时间机器往柜子里面拖）
DOCTOR: Now the other one. Steady.
现在, 另外一头, 稳住
JAMIE: Right. Now, where's Victoria?
好。对了, Victoria 在哪儿
DOCTOR: Quick Jamie, the time switch!
快 Jamie, 那个时间开关
JAMIE: Twenty-eight, Doctor. Hey, Doctor, Kemel must have dropped this.
28秒, 博士。嘿, 这肯定是 Kemel 掉下来的
DOCTOR: Jamie!
(The Doctor and Jamie help Waterfield to stand in the machine.)
（博士和 Jamie 帮助 Waterfield 在机器里面站稳）
JAMIE: We'll find Victoria and Kemel too.
我们得找到 Victoria, 还有 Kemel
(Then they get in.)
（然后他们进了Daleks 的时间机器）
(Victoria comes to and sees that Kemel is squeezing
out a cloth from a bowl of water.)
（Victoria 苏醒过来, 看到 Kemel 正在拧一块手绢, 那手绢显然刚从一碗水里捞出来）
VICTORIA: Dear Kemel. Oh, there. Are any of the others here?
亲爱的 Kemel, 噢, 这里还有其他人吗？
(He shakes his head.)
（Kemel 摇摇头）
VICTORIA: The Daleks?
有 Daleks？
(He nods.)
（Kemel 点点头）
DALEK: You will wait here.
你们在这里等着
VICTORIA: Oh, Mr. Maxtible.
哦, Maxtible 先生
MAXTIBLE: Oh, what are you doing here?
啊, 你在这里做什么？
VICTORIA: Don't know. Nor even where here may be.
不知道, 甚至都不知道这里是哪里
(The Dalek leaves.)
（Dalek 离开了）
MAXTIBLE: Oh, we've been transported to the Dalek planet, my dear. To Skaro.
哦, 我们被传送到了 Dalek 母星, 亲爱的, 它叫 Skaro
VICTORIA: I don't understand you.
我听不明白
MAXTIBLE: A little journey through space.
穿越空间的一趟小旅程
VICTORIA: They've taken us somewhere. Is that what you mean?
Away from your house?
他们把我们带到了某个地方, 你是这个意思吗？不在你的房子里了？
MAXTIBLE: Oh, far away. Far, far away.
噢, 离那里很远, 很远
VICTORIA: But why? What do they want?
但是为什么？他们想要什么？
MAXTIBLE: Well, I know why I am here. But why you are here,
I have not the faintest idea.
嗯, 我知道我什么在这里。但你为什么在这里, 我就一点都不清楚了
VICTORIA: You seem to understand them. Ask them.
看来你很了解他们, 那问问他们
MAXTIBLE: Don't be foolish, girl. I shall do no such thing.
别犯傻了, 姑娘。我才不做这种事情
VICTORIA: And where's my father?
还有, 我的父亲在哪儿？
MAXTIBLE: I do not know. I'm not a nursemaid to your father.
我不知道, 我又不是你父亲的保育员
DALEK: Follow me.
跟我来
MAXTIBLE: Of course, I shall do my best for you.
The matter is really entirely out of my hands.
当然, 我会尽量帮你的。现在的情况真的完全不在我的掌握之中了
VICTORIA: It's no good. He won't help us.
这没用的, 他不会帮我们
VICTORIA: Think so? Wish I did.
你这么想？期望我也是
VICTORIA: Don't worry Kemel, I shall protect you.
别担心 Kemel, 我会保护你
VICTORIA: I shall see they do you no harm.
我不会让他们伤害你的
VICTORIA: Yes, I suppose it was a bit silly.
是的, 我觉得这有一点傻
VICTORIA: Oh well. Maybe between us we can fight them.
We must face it out together.
噢, 好吧, 也许我们两个可以跟他们斗。我们必须一起面对
WATERFIELD: And that is the Dalek city?
这就是 Dalek 之城？
DOCTOR: Yes, it is.
是的, 它就是
JAMIE: I've scouted around, but I can't see any water.
我四周探查过了, 没看见有水
WATERFIELD: Oh, please don't bother. I feel much better.
哦, 别麻烦了, 我感觉好多了
DOCTOR: Are you sure?
你确定吗？
WATERFIELD: Yes.
是的
DOCTOR: Come along then. We must get along.
过来吧, 我们必须一起
JAMIE: You mean just walk into the city?
你是说用脚走进这城市？
DOCTOR: Oh, no Jamie. The city is all around us. At least,
um, it's beneath us. Come along.
哦, 不, Jamie, 这座城市就在我们周围。至少, 它在我们下面, 过来吧
(The Doctor moves a boulder, revealing a hold in the rock face)
（博士移动了一块大圆石, 石头表面露出了一个洞）
JAMIE: How long have you known that's there?
你什么时候知道这里有个入口？
DOCTOR: Not a sound. I think the Daleks are in for a little surprise.
别出声。我想 Dalek 会得到一个小惊喜
(They enter the cave.)
（他们进入了洞内 )
DALEK: Where is the Doctor?
博士在那里?
MAXTIBLE: I had no time to get him.
我没时间去找他
DALEK: No time?
没有时间？
MAXTIBLE: I was told my house was going to be destroyed. Why?
我被告知我的房子马上就要被炸毁了。为什么？
DALEK: You did not bring the Doctor?!
你没把博士带来？！
MAXTIBLE: Everything I possess is in that house. Everything.
What right had you or anyone to destroy it?
我喜欢的所有东西都在那栋房子里, 所有。你有什么权利把它毁掉？
MAXTIBLE: All these years of labour, all these years of research
- destroyed through this caprice of yours.
这些年所有的辛苦, 所有的研究 —— 都因为你们的反复无常给毁了
MAXTIBLE: My laboratory - the only real thing in the whole of my existence - destroyed.
我的实验室, 我存活于世唯一真实的东西, 被毁掉了
MAXTIBLE: I, Theodore Maxtible, made a bargain with you,
and I demand to know... ah, ah!
我, Theodore Maxtible, 咱们谈好了的, 现在我要求知道。。。啊, 啊！
DALEK: Rights? You have disobeyed a Dalek command.
You must obey the Dalek command.
权利？你违背了 Dalek 的命令。你必须服从 Dalek 的命令
DALEK: Exterminate. Destroy.
终结。毁灭
MAXTIBLE: I swear... I swear... I swear it's not my fault.
I swear it's not my fault. I... No!
我发誓。。我发誓。。我发誓, 不是我的错, 我发誓不是我的错。我。。。不！
DALEK: Move.
走
MAXTIBLE: What's happening? What are you going to do with me?
发生了什么？你们打算拿我怎样样？
DALEK: Obey. Move.
服从。走。
DALEK: These humans are still here.
那几个人类还在这里
DALEK: Then other humans are inside the city.
那城市里面还有其他的人类
(The Daleks leaves.)
（Daleks 都离开了)
VICTORIA: "Other humans inside the city", Kemel! Listen!
”城市里面有其他的人类“, Kemel, 听！
DALEK: Emergency. Emergency. Human beings detected in city! Emergency! Emergency!
紧急情况, 紧急情况。探测到有人类在城市里。紧急情况, 紧急情况！
VICTORIA: Maybe it's Jamie and the Doctor. Oh, Kemel, there's a chance. A chance.
有可能是 Jamie 和博士。哦, Kemel, 有机会了, 有机会
DALEK: Intruders detected. Emergency! Emergency! Human beings detected in city.
检测到闯入者。紧急情况, 紧急情况！检测到有人类在城市里
DALEK: Emergency! Emergency! Intruders detected. All Daleks to observation stations.
紧急情况, 紧急情况！检测到闯入者。所有 Dalek 进入观察岗
DALEK: Repeat. All Daleks to observation stations. Emergency!
重复。所有 Dalek 进入观察岗。紧急情况!
(They are moving along a metal pathway, with a rock wall one side
and a large drop the other.)
（他们沿着一条金属做成的小路前进, 小路一边是石头墙, 另一边是深渊)
DALEK: Stop! What is that mark?
停下！ 那个标志是什么？
DALEK 2: That is my name.
那是我的名字
DALEK: Name?
名字?
DALEK 2: The Doctor gave it to me.
博士给我取的
DALEK: Doctor?
博士
DALEK 2: Yes. He is my friend.
是的, 他是我的朋友
DALEK: Follow me.
跟我来
(The two Daleks move down the corridor.)
（两个 Daleks 沿着走廊走过去)
(A Dalek is herding Victoria and Kemel down the corridor.)
（一个 Daleks 驱赶着 Victoria 和 Kemel 沿着走廊往前走）
(Victoria, Kemel and the Dalek enter the room.)
（Victoria, Kemel 和这个 Dalek 进了房间）
DALEK: Remain here.
呆在这里
MAXTIBLE: What is happening? Do you know? They say there are
other human beings in the city.
什么情况？你们知道吗？他们说城市里有其他人类
MAXTIBLE: Why don't you answer me, you little fool.
No one can help you here. No one but me.
你为什么不回答我, 你个小傻瓜。这里没有人能够帮助你, 除了我没有人
DALEK: Silence. Follow me. You, wait.
安静。随我来。你, 等着
MAXTIBLE: I can't see anything.
我什么也看不见
DALEK: Move.
走
MAXTIBLE: Where are you taking me?
你要带我去哪里？
VICTORIA: Oh, what are they doing to him?
噢, 他们在对他干什么？
DALEK: You follow. You will wait.
你跟上。你等着
VICTORIA: I'll do as you say.
你们说什么我就做什么
DALEK: Move forward, alone.
往前走, 单独
JAMIE: That was a human voice, I tell you.
那是一个人的声音, 我跟你说
DOCTOR: Perhaps it was, Jamie
也许是吧, Jamie
DOCTOR: We must go more quickly.
我们必须再走快点
JAMIE: Victoria. That was Victoria's voice.
Victoria. 那是 Victoria 的声音
DOCTOR: You can't. Where are you running to? Well, you mustn't.
You'll go over the edge!
你不能, 你跑哪儿去？嘿, 你不能！你会掉下去的！
DALEK: Doctor, I am your friend.
博士, 我是你的朋友
JAMIE: One of your experiments, Doctor. For a moment I thought we were done for!
你的一个实验品, 博士。有那么一会儿我都觉得我们完蛋了
DOCTOR: What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
DALEK: Omega.
欧米伽
DOCTOR: Oh, I see.
哦, 我知道了
DALEK: I have come to lead you.
我是来给你带路的
DOCTOR: Thank you.
谢谢你
JAMIE: Oh, careful.
哦, 小心点
DOCTOR: Oh, ah... I'm all right. Oh, thank you. Ah, lead on.
噢, 啊。。我没事。哦,谢谢你。带路吧
(The Docotor examines the Dalek's base.)
（博士检查了这个Dalek的底座）
DALEk: Follow me.
跟我来
DOCTOR: What was that screaming?
那是什么叫声？
DALEK: A prisoner.
一个囚犯
DOCTOR: Where?
在哪里
DALEK: Follow me. I will show you.
跟我来, 我带你看
JAMIE: What are you doing?
你在干什么？
DOCTOR: Think I don't know my own mark? That wasn't the real Omega at all.
你觉得我不知道自己刻的字？那根本不是真正的欧米伽
JAMIE: Up to all sorts of tricks, aren't they?
他们的伎俩还真是很多啊, 是不？
WATERFIELD: Oh, please. We must reach my daughter.
噢, 别聊了, 我们得赶去我女儿那里
MAXTIBLE: I tell you, they forced me. They threatened to kill us all.
我跟你说, 都是他们逼我的。他们威胁要杀死我们全部
MAXTIBLE: First of all, they ordered me to scream
and I was to make you do the same.
首先, 他们命令我喊叫, 你们也一样fixme
VICTORIA: And you had to do as you were told?
那你就不得不按他们说的做？
MAXTIBLE: I tell you, they threatened to kill me.
我跟你说, 他们威胁要杀死我
VICTORIA: You came up behind me in the dark and twisted my arm.
你在黑暗中从我被后冒出来, 扭了我的胳膊
MAXTIBLE: And what else could I do?
那我还能干什么？
VICTORIA: Oh, if only I'd realised. Why do you think they wanted us to scream like that?
我要是早明白就好了。你不想想, 他们为什么要我们像那样惨叫？
MAXTIBLE: I've no idea.
我也不知道
VICTORIA: You know perfectly well.
你完全知道。
VICTORIA: There are other people in the city.
They wanted to draw them on. Trap them.
还有其他人类在城里，他们想把那些人吸引过来, 抓住他们
Oh, if only I could have thought quickly. Oh, Kemel.
我要是能早点能想到这个就好了, 噢, Kemel
(They climb through a g??? into a corridor in the Dalek city.)
（博士他们爬到了 Dalek 城市的一条走道上）
(The Doctor looks up and down the corridor,
he decides which way to go and starts to move.)
（博士往走道两头看了看, 挑了一头, 继续往前走）
(Jamie and Waterfield follow.)
（Jamie 和 Waterfield 紧随其后）
(A Dalek is watching them.)
（一个 Dalek 正等着他们）
DOCTOR: No, no. I don't like the look of this. Back the way we came.
不，不，我不喜欢这个样子。回到我们来的路上去
(Two Daleks block their exit.)
（两个 Daleks 堵住他们的退路）
DALEK: Follow me.
跟我来
(They follow the black Dalek.)
（他们只能跟着黑色 Dalek 走）
EMPEROR: Doctor!
博士!
Look at the size of that thing.
EMPEROR: So, you are the Doctor?
这么说, 你就是那位博士？
DOCTOR: We meet at last. I wondered if we ever would.
EMPEROR: The experiment is over.
实验已经结束了
DOCTOR: Yes, I have implanted the "Human Factor" in the three
Daleks that you gave me... When I say run, run!
是的, 你给我的三个 Dalek, 我已经给他们植入了“人类特质”。。。当但我说跑的时候, 跑！
EMPEROR: Speak louder.
大声说话
DOCTOR: Promise me, Jamie. I was merely telling my friend
that the day of the Daleks is coming to an end.
答应我, Jamie —— 我只是在告诉我的朋友们, Dalek 的日子到头了
EMPEROR: Explain.
解释
DOCTOR: It's very simple. Somewhere in the Dalek race
there are three Daleks with the "Human Factor"
这很简单, 在 Dalek 族群中某处, 现在有三个带有“人类特质”的 Dalek
DOCTOR: Gradually, they will come to question.
They will persuade other Daleks to question.
慢慢地, 他们就会问问题, 他们也会感染其他 Dalek 来问问题
DOCTOR: You will have a rebellion on your planet!
你的星球上就会掀起叛乱！
EMPEROR: NO!
不会！
DOCTOR: I say, yes. I've beaten you and I don't care what you do to me now.
我说, 会！我已经打败了你们, 现在我才不在乎你要拿我怎么样了
EMPEROR: Silence. The "Human Factor" showed us what the "Dalek Factor" was.
安静。“人类特质”向我们展示了“DaleK特质“应该是什么
DOCTOR: What?
什么？
DOCTOR: Well, what does that mean?
那么，那又意味着什么？
EMPEROR: Without knowing, you have shown the Daleks what their own strength is.
你在并不知情的状态下, 你向 Dalek 展示了他们自己的力量所在
WATERFIELD: While you were doing one thing, they were really making you do another.
让你做一件事，但实际上是在让你做另外一件事
EMPEROR: The "Human Factor" is useless.
”人类特质”是没有用的
DOCTOR: You still have those three Daleks to contend with.
但你仍然有三个 Dalek 要对付
EMPEROR: They will be impregnated with the "Dalek Factor".
Your discovery, but your work is not over.
他们将会被植入"Dalek特质“, 你的探索和工作还没有完啊
DOCTOR: I won't work for you!
我不会为你工作的！
EMPEROR: You will obey!
你会服从的！
JAMIE: What is the "Dalek Factor"?
“Dalek特质”是什么？
DOCTOR: You want me to guess? It means to obey, to fight,
to destroy, to exterminate. I won't do it.
你想让我猜吗？它意味着服从、战争、毁灭、终结。我不会干的
EMPEROR: Watch!
看着！
JAMIE: The TARDIS, Doctor!
TARDIS, 博士!
EMPEROR: You will take the "Dalek Factor. "
You will spread it to the entire history of Earth!
你要提取出"Dalek特质”, 并将它散布到地球的整个历史中去！